# **Atul Meshram**

# **User Experience Designer**



www.atulmeshram.in



in www.linkedin.com/in/atulmeshram



+91-8050606549

atul.meshram.akm@gmail.com

HSR layout, Bangalore, PIN - 560102, INDIA

#### **About Me**

I am passionate about the way people use technology. I love to interact with the users to understand their expectations and unpleasant experiences from the product and use their insights to create simple and beautiful interfaces that have a high degree of usability.

## **Education**

Interaction Design Specialisation University of California, San Diego Coursera

Master of Computer Applications Specialisation in Computer Graphics NIT Karnataka, Surathkal **8.5 CGPA** 

**GNIIT - Software Engineering** NIIT Ltd. A+ Grade

**Bachelor of Computer Applications** PRSU, Raipur 78%

Class 12th **CBSE - All India** 

81%

Class 10th **CBSE - All India** 80%

# **Professional Work Experience**

## ■ Standard Chartered 'PayC' App

Accolite Software India Pvt. Ltd.

[November 2017 - Present]

PayC is a UPI banking app from Standard Chartered bank that lets transfer money instantly.

- Discussions and requirement gathering from the client.
- Designed high-fidelity clickable prototypes for conceptual Interaction Design.
- User Research and Comparative Analysis with other trending apps in the market.

Interactive Video Prototypes: https://goo.gl/efaykv

■ FedEx FRMS - Accolite Software India Pvt. Ltd.

[September 2017 - Present]

An iPad App for FedEx pilot fatigue management.

- Analysed existing web application and redesigned modules for iPad app.
- Designed high-fidelity clickable prototypes.
- UI asset distribution; application flow, animations and behavior guide for developers.

■ BT Business App - Accolite Software India Pvt. Ltd. [July 2016 - October 2017]

A mobile application providing all business services to BT Group PLC customers.

- Interacted, analysed and interpreted customer needs and create a pleasant user experience.
- Designed application flow, created wireframes and high-fidelity mock-ups.
- Developed 'Payment' page UI using Javascript, CSS3 & HTML5.
- Reviewed and guided developers and testers to get the expected application design.

Apple App Store: https://goo.gl/m7EY5Z Google Play Store: https://goo.gl/1KkVrL

■ UKB SaaS - Accolite Software India Pvt. Ltd.

Software Engineer - Intern

[January 2016 - July 2016]

Web app to manage mobile products and related services of UKB SaaS project owned by BT Group.

- Developed fully functional application modules using C#, AngularJS and ASP MVC.
- Wrote unit test cases on JasminJS by configuring KarmaJS framework.

#### **UX/UI Skills**

Web & Mobile UX/UI Patterns **UX Strategy & Planning** User Research Wireframe & Prototyping Interaction Design **Heuristic Evaluation Usability Testing Comparative Analysis** 

# **Programming**

**Softwares & Tools JavaScript** Sketch & Plugins HTML5 Flinto CSS3 Adobe Photoshop C# Adobe Illustrator C InVision Swift (Beginner) AxureRP **Google Analytics** Visual Studio Code

## Leadership

Design Strategy **Team Coordination** Work Review **Project Planning Training & Mentorship** 

**Design Personas** 

Wireless Headphone 'Air' - App Concept | https://goo.gl/UFCS3g Farmers' Suicides - Infographic Report | https://goo.gl/ibxSBF